Now for the main issue...
(ヤマト)ここからが本題だ。
その バディチームを➡
Now I'm going to determine
the Buddy Teams.
今 決めておく。
First, Sakura and I will be one team!
(ヤマト)まずは ボクとサクラのチーム。
ナルトとサイのチームだ。
The other team will be...
Naruto and Sai.
《ナルト : オレが…。
Me...?
コイツと…》
with him...?
《サクラ : 私とヤマト隊長が チームを組む》
Captain Yamato and I
will form one team.
And...
《そして…。
the other team will be Naruto and Sai.
もう一つのチームが ナルトとサイ…》
(サイ)よろしく。
Looking forward to it
《また 作り笑いかよ。
There's that fake smile again.
Damn it!
クッソ…》
Captain Yamato.
ヤマト隊長！
(ヤマト)なんだい？ ナルト。
What is it, Naruto?
なんで…
なんでオレが コイツと…。
Why... Why do I have to team up
with him?
何か？
Is there a problem?
りょ… 了解だってばよ…。
U-Understood.
Good.
よろしい。
((綱手 : そうか…。
I see...
(綱手)しかたない…。
It can't be helped...
とりあえず ナルトは
お前がコントロールしておけ。
For the time being,
you keep Naruto under control.
Yes...
(サクラ)はい…))
あの… ヤマト隊長。
Um... Captain Yamato.
なんだい？
(サクラ)チームを組むなら➡
What is it?
I think Naruto and I would
make a better team.
私とナルトのほうが いいと思います。
前から一緒にやってますし➡
We've been working together
for a while
and we know each other quite well, so.
お互いのことも
よく わかってますから。
Right-right!. That's my Sakura-chan.
うん うん…
さっすが サクラちゃん。
(ヤマト)サクラ。
(サクラ)はい。
Sakura.
Yes?
You're the only Medical Ninja
on this team.
キミは このチームで唯一の医療忍者だ。
負傷させるわけには
いかないから➡
We can't let you get hurt,
and that is why you'll be with me.
ボクが つくんだ。
わかるだろ？
You understand, right?
はい…。
Yes, I do.
(ヤマト)さっき サイも言っていたが➡
As Sai said earlier,
we can assume the enemy
will be very skilled...
相手は 相当の手練と考えられる。
A mistake in teamwork
could prove fatal.
味方の連携ミスは 命取りになるよ。
言いたいこともあるだろうが➡
I'm sure you have all something
to say about this,
今は まず…
任務のことを考えてくれ。
but just concentrate
on the mission for now.
(サクラ)はい。
わかったってばよ。
Yes, sir.
Got it...
大蛇丸のアジトが
どこにあるか 知らないが…。
We don't know where
Orochimaru's hideout is.
But the Akatsuki spy is probably
on his way
暁のスパイも 天地橋に
向かっている頃だろうしね。
to the Tenchi Bridge right about now.
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forgotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenain deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
EVERDAY hereafter is a shining day.
everyday kono saki mo shining day
Unchanging singin', a bright morning smile.
kawarazu singin' hikaru asa no smile
This is the last farewell on funny days.
kore de miosame no funny days
Leaping into the future I see. Go far, dream of my heart.
tobidatsu future mezashita go far kokoro no dream of
I'll go the distance, the endless sky is blue.
i'll go the distance mihatenu sora wa blue
I've hitched a ride on the star ship, this is the best forever trip.
norikonda star ship kore ga saigo no forever trip
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenai deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah, it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
Thank you my friend.
thank you my friend
Ah even now,
aa ano hi no koto
I still remember that day.
ima demo mada oboeteru kara
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah those days that will never come back.
aa mou nidoto sou modoranai days
Woah I'll go the distance!
woah i'll go the distance
"Tenchi Bridge"
Simulation
来た…。
Here he comes...
こっちの準備は まだか？
Aren't we ready yet...?
来た。
There he is!
クッソ～ 合図は まだかよ！
Damn it, where's the signal?!
合図だっ！
There's the signal.
待ちやがれっ！
Hold it!
フンッ！
(ヤマト)うぉっ！
(サクラ)ナルトッ 今よ！
Now, Naruto.
行くぞっ サイ！
Let's go, Sai.
((ヤマト : 今の話を踏まえて➡
Based on what we just talked about,
although I generally don't do
this very often...
ふだんは あまりやらないんだが➡
tomorrow we'll devote half a day
to a team-play simulation.
明日 半日をチームプレイの
シミュレーションにあてる。
A simulation?
シミュレーション？
(ヤマト)そうだ。
That's right.
(ヤマト)ボクは キミらを
ファイル上の情報でしか知らない。
All I know about you guys is
what I've read in your files.
キミたちの戦い方や 戦闘スキル➡
I want to get an idea
術の系統なども把握しておきたい。
of your fighting styles, battle skills
and Jutsu types...
ボク自身の… 目でね。
with my own eyes.
(ヤマト)それに お互いを
よく知っておくことで➡
And the cooperation of the team
should get smoother
チームの連携もスムーズになる。
if we learn about each other.
Uh-huh, cooperation, eh?
ケッ… 連携ねぇ…。
慎重すぎると
思うかも知れないが➡
You might think
I'm being too cautious...
これが ボクのやり方なんでね。
But this is how I do things.
(つきあってもらうよ))
You will go along with it.
ぐぉ～！
うわっ クッソ～！
Damn it!
少しは本気でこいっ！
Come at me for real!
うわっ！
まだまだ！
Not nearly good enough.
ん？
うわっ！
うっ うう…。
とぉりゃ～!!
《忍法 超獣偽画！》
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll.
No way am I letting go!
放すかってばよ！
Wha--?!
おっ！ うわっ…。
Why are you grabbing me, too?!
なんで オレまで…。
Hey, Sai! Do something about this!
コラッ！ サイ！ これ なんとか
しろってばよ！
《あっちか…》
That way, huh?
H-Hey! Where are you going, Sai?!
なっ おい！ どこ行くんだよ サイ！
もう ヤマト隊長は
捕まえたんだから➡
I've already captured Captain Yamato,
so hurry up and untie me!
早く これ ほどけってばよ！
ナルト！
Naruto!
(サクラ)何やってんの!?
それ ヤマト隊長じゃないわよ！
What're you doing?!
That isn't Captain Yamato.
えっ！ え？
Huh? What?
"You Fail"
はぁ～!!
What the hell is this?!
なんだ こりゃ!?
Damn it! Hey, Sai!
クッソ～!! コラ～ サイ!!
Hurry up and untie this snake!
さっさと この蛇 ほどきやがれ！
(ヤマト)よく捕まえたね サイ。
You did well to capture me, Sai.
《なるほど…
これは 想像以上の腕前だな。
I see...
He's more skilled than I imagined.
これほどの忍を カカシ班の
補充要員に充ててくるとは…》
I can't believe a Shinobi this good
was assigned to Team Kakashi
as an alternate.
((もう一人…
あの暗部養成部門 「根」から➡
An additional member...
a new recruit from
the Anbu Black Ops Training Division
新人が一人 カカシ班に配属される。
will be dispatched to Team Kakashi...
「根」からですか？
From... the Foundation...?
(綱手)ただ…。
なんです？
However...
(ソイツの行動には
注意を払っておけ))
What is it...?
Keep a close watch on his actions...
《綱手様の心配も➡
Tsunade-sama's concerns may not
have been groundless.
杞憂ではないのかも
知れないな…》
やい やい やい！
Hey, hey, hey!
テメエ～ サイ！
You bastard, Sai!
《サイ : なるほど…》
I see.
((ん～… しゃ～!!))
《あれを引きちぎるとは
すごい力だ。
She has incredible strength
to be able to tear that snake...
二度と 殴られたくないですね》
I don't want to get hit by her again.
解！
Release.
よしっ！
シミュレーションは これで終わりだ。
All right, that's the end of the simulation.
んっ！
テメェ！
何です？
You bastard!
お前 仲間って言葉 知ってっか？
What is it?
Don't you know what
the word "comrade" is?
テメェは… 仲間って言葉➡
Listen, you!
I'm asking you if you know
what the word "comrade" is!
知ってっかって
聞いてんだってばよ！
(サイ)もちろん 知ってますが…。
Of course I do...
それが 何か？
What of it?
"Comrade"
オレが言いてぇのは
そういうことじゃねえ！
That's not what I'm trying to say.
ちょっと… ナルト！
H-Hey, Naruto.
個人能力の低さを
人のせいにしないでください。
Please don't blame your lack of
individual competence on others.
なんだと…！
What did you say?!
((グオォォー!!
クソッ…！
(ヤマト)少しは 本気でこい！))
Damn it!
Come at me for real!
(サイ)キミが 隊長の安い挑発に
のらなければ➡
If you hadn't let the Captain get
a rise out of you...
ボクが身を隠していることが
バレずにすんだ。
I could've remained hidden
without being exposed.
(サイ)そうすれば
隊長を捕獲するのに➡
And it wouldn't have been
this much trouble
こんなに
手間取ることもなかった。
to capture the Captain.
どういうことだってばよ…。
What do you mean?
せっかく ボクに変化したって➡
Even if you go to the trouble
of transforming into me...
(サイ)キミの術を使えば
影分身だと すぐバレる。
you'll be exposed as
a Shadow Clone immediately
if you use one of your Jutsu.
(サイ)あれで こちらの作戦を
見抜いた隊長は➡
Because of that,
the Captain saw through our strategy
かわり身を使い
森の中に逃げ込んだ。
and escaped into the forest
using a Substitution.
だったら…
かわり身だってわかってんなら➡
Then why didn't you break
the Jutsu right away
なんで…
すぐ 術 解かなかったんだよ？
if you knew it was a Substitution?
冷静さを欠いたヤツを
かばいながら戦うのは➡
It isn't ideal to fight
while protecting someone who
has lost his cool.
理想的じゃない。
(サイ)任務の成功の可能性を考えて
判断し 行動しただけだ。
All I did was consider the best way
to successfully complete the mission,
make a judgment and take action.
オレは 認めねえぞ！
I won't acknowledge you.
お前なんか…
仲間として カカシ班として➡
I'll never acknowledge
the likes of you
as a comrade or as a member
of Team Kakashi!
ぜってえ 認めねえってばよ！
はぁ… やっぱり ムリかな。
I guess these two just won't work
as a team, huh?
この２人の チームというのは…。
(サイ)サスケ君なら
どうしましたかね？
I wonder what Sasuke-kun would've done.
キミをかばいながら
戦ってくれたでしょうか？
Would he have fought
while protecting you?
キミからしたら
カカシ班の仲間ですからね。
He's a Team Kakashi
comrade to you, right?
《ダメだ… ナルトのヤツ…➡
No good...
Naruto won't be able to put up
with this any longer.
これ以上 我慢できるわけない…》
里を裏切り キミを傷つけた人を➡
If you call someone who betrayed
his village and hurt you...
仲間と呼ぶのならね…。
a comrade, that is.
《ナルト…》
Naruto.
《まずい…！》
その仲間を救うためなら➡
This is not good.
If it's to save that comrade,
なんだってやるさ…。
then I'll do whatever it takes.
お前とだって… 組んでやる。
I'll even team up with you.
《ナルト…》
Naruto.
(サイ)なぜ… 彼は サスケ君のことを
あんなにまで…？
Why does he feel so strongly
about Sasuke-kun?
ナルトは… サスケ君のことを
兄弟みたいに思ってるから…。
It's because Naruto...
thinks of Sasuke-kun like a brother.
あなたも お兄さんいるんだよね？
You've got a brother, too,
don't you...?
その気持 少しはわかるでしょ…？
You should understand
a little about how he feels.
(サイ)いや… まったく。
No, not at all.
(サイ)絵のタイトルの話をしたよね。
I told you about titles for
my drawings, right?
((正確には
タイトルをつけようとしても➡
To be exact,
I couldn't title one of my drawings
even if I wanted to...
つけられないんだ。
(サイ)何も 思い浮かばない…。
何も 感じないんだよ…))
Nothing comes to mind.
I don't... feel anything.
ボクには 感情ってものがないんだ。
I have no such thing as emotions.
何も感じないって…。
What do you mean...
感情がないって どういうこと…？
you don't feel anything
or have any emotions...?
言葉どおり そういうことだよ。
I mean just what I said.
だからって
あなたも兄弟がいるなら➡
Even so, if you have a brother,
その兄弟が
いなくなったときのことを➡
you should be able to imagine
what it would be like to lose him, right?
少しは想像できるでしょ？
ん？ あぁ… まぁね。
Hm...? Yeah, well...
you could say that.
兄さん もう死んでるし。
My brother's dead, after all.
だったら余計に。
Then all the more...
(サイ)あぁいう顔をすれば
よかったのかなぁ。
I wonder if I should've looked like that.
何が言いたいの？
What're you trying to say?
(サイ)いやね…
兄さんが死んだときに➡
Well, I didn't know what kind of look
to make when my nii-san died...
どういう顔を作ればいいか➡
わからなかったから。
顔を作るって…。
Look to make?
《コイツ…》
This guy...
お話は そこまでだよ。
That's enough talking.
そろそろ出発するから➡
We're moving out pretty soon,
so gather your things.
荷物を取ってきな。
サイ 本当なら さっき私➡
Sai, normally I would've pounded
you good back there...
また あなたを殴り飛ばしてた。
もう一度
サスケ君のことを悪く言ったら➡
I told you I wouldn't hold back if
you spoke ill of Sasuke-kun again, right?
手加減しないって言ったでしょ。
でも そうしなかったのは➡
But I didn't do that
ナルトが サスケ君を救うためなら➡
because even
though you insult Sasuke-kun,
サスケ君をバカにするアンタとでも
組むって➡
Naruto said he would team up with you
if it meant saving Sasuke-kun.
言ったからよ。
アンタが どんなヤツだろうと➡
No matter what kind of guy you are...
サスケ君を救うためなら➡
I must not hurt you if it means
saving Sasuke-kun.
アンタを傷つけるわけには
いかないから。
サクラさん キミは ナルト君に…。
Sakura-san, in regards to Naruto-kun...
うん… 優しいっていうのかな。
Yeah, I guess I'd say you're nice to him.
こういうの。
本には こうありましたね。
I once read something
like this in a book.
なぜ
そんな感情が湧いてくるのか➡
I don't know why such feelings arise.
ボクには わかりませんが。
みんな 早く行くってばよ。
Guys.
Let's get a move on.
明日の昼までに着かなかったら➡
This will all come to nothing
元も子もねえからな。
if we don't get there
by tomorrow afternoon.
そろそろだ。
We're almost there.
ここで準備をしてから➡
We'll head for the bridge once
we're finished getting ready here.
橋に向かうよ。
Reach for it, reach for it, far away.
todoke todoke tooku e
Now I trust these revived tears to you.
ima wo kishikaisei namida azukete
It begins.
hajimare
A long, long story about you
nagai nagai kimi monogatari
"Tears", "tears".
namidatte namidatte
I want to shed them in happy times
ureshii toki ni nagashitai
So what if I want them to float in pretty puddles?
kirei na mizutamari ukabetai no wa nani
The southern sky,
minami no sora ni
It twinkles.
matataiteiru
From all of the stars meeting.
hoshi no kazu hodo no deai kara
Learning about love, receiving a map.
ai wo manandari chizu wo morattari
Are connected.
tsunagatteku
Reach for it, reach for it, far away.
todoke todoke tooku e
(２人)木ノ葉 なんでも調査隊！
今日の疑問は
波の国のタヅナさんから。
Now I trust these revived tears to you.
ima wo kishikaisei namida azukete
(サクラ)「忍者の階級が超わからん。
ワシらにも わかるように
説明してくれ」だって。
Someday a new page will turn.
itsuka mekuru peeji ni
お～ 超 懐かしいってばよ！
I'm sure it'll be filled with lots of people
kitto takusan no hito ga afureru
それじゃあ 上から紹介するわね。
(サクラ)上忍は正規部隊の頂点。
数は少ないけど➡
It begins,
hajimare
一人ひとりが
破格の実力の持ち主よ。
A long, long story about you.
nagai nagai kimi monogatari
続いて 特別上忍。
各分野のスペシャリストで➡
適性によって
専門的な任務に就くわ。
Next Episode
Damn it. That spy jerk isn't here yet?!
イビキ先生は 尋問のエキスパート。
エビス先生は教育の専門家ね。
It won't be that easy.
Our opponent is highly skilled.
お次は私たち中忍。
Being overly cautious is just fine.
主に下忍たちをまとめる隊長役よ。
But if we're too cautious,
オレだけいなくて
なんか や～な感じ。
we might attract the spy's suspicion
and our timing to capture him
will get thrown off.
(サクラ)最後は下忍ね。
やっと オレの階級だな。
That's true.
Shh! It looks like he's here.
時間もないし 今さら
説明の必要もないわよね。
Took him long enough. Hey, th-that's...!
あらっ サクラちゃん…。
No way! It can't be!
タヅナさん みんな またね～。
The Tenchi Bridge
He's the Akatsuki spy?!
終わってるし！
Next episode: "The Tenchi Bridge"
The Leaf Ask-Us-Anything
Investigation Team!
Today's question comes from Tazuna-san
from the Land of Waves.
"I so don't understand
the ninja class system.”
"Explain it so I can understand it."
That's what he said.
Ooh! That really takes me back!
Hokage
Jonin
Specialised Jonin
Chunin
Genin
Hidden
Leaf's
Regulatory
Board
Hokage
Jonin
Specialised Jonin
Chunin
Genin
Hidden
Leaf's
Regulatory
Board
Hokage
Jonin
Specialised Jonin
Chunin
Genin
Hidden
Leaf's
Regulatory
Board
Hokage
Jonin
Specialised Jonin
Chunin
Genin
Hidden
Leaf's
Regulatory
Board
Okay, we'll introduce the classes
from the top.
Jonin are the pinnacle
of the regular units.
There aren't many of them,
but each one possesses incredible ability.
Next are the special jonin.
They're specialists in different fields...
and are assigned to specialized missions
depending on aptitude.
Ibiki-sensei is an expert at interrogation.
And Ebisu-sensei is
an education specialist, I guess.
Next are us chunin.
Our main role is to keep
the genin together as team leaders.
It kind of sucks that
I'm the only one not in the group.
And lastly, the genin.
Finally, it's my class.
We're out of time, and besides,
it's kind of self-explanatory, isn't it?
Hey, Sakura-chan.
— Explain it a little more!
— Tazuna-san, everyone, see you around.
Hey, it's over!
THIRD QUESTION: NINJA'S RANK
SOLVED!